Hey everybody, welcome to this A2
English listening practice video. I hope
you're doing well and that you're ready
to practice your listening with another
video. Today I want to talk about
learning English with music. This uh
honestly is not something that I have
really done as a language learner. I
haven't really used a lot of music to
learn other languages. So, personally, I
don't have tons of experience with this,
but I know that many people love music.
I'm sure many of you love music, and I
know that some people like using music
to help them learn languages. So, it's
actually a tool that you can use to help
you learn English. And I want to talk
about that today. Uh before I do that, I
want to remind you that if you want more
advanced content, if this is a little
easy for you to understand, then make
sure to sign up for my advanced podcast
episodes. That link is in the
description below. And then also you can
check out my US Conversations podcast in
which I talk to different people from
all over the country. We have normal
conversations at normal speed. It's a
lot of fun. And of course, I provide the
transcript for each conversation. So,
you can also check that out. That link
is also down below. So, let's talk about
learning English using music. I'm not
the most musical person, and maybe
that's why I haven't really tried using
a lot of music to learn languages. Uh,
however, recently I've thought more
about this because um I was watching a
Greek video. Uh, I actually watched it
many times uh as I've spoken about a
lot. Uh, I like to use repetition as a
language learner. So there's a Greek
video that I have watched many times and
uh that video talks about learning uh
Greek using Greek music and the person
who made the video uh put uh a part of
two different songs, Greek songs in the
video uh to like demonstrate something
And what's funny is uh I don't like
those songs that the person put in the
video. Um I didn't really pay attention
much to those songs uh those parts of
the songs that she put in there uh the
first couple times that I watched that
video. But I realized after listening to
or watching that video a few times that
I could uh like almost sing those um
parts of those Greek songs that she
included in there. Even though I did not
try to learn them, uh I didn't care
about them. I uh realized that these
songs stayed in my head and there was
even uh new vocabulary
in both of those parts of those songs
that I know now simply because of those
songs. The reason why I'm talking about
uh that experience is because it made me
think of how um it made me think about
how uh powerful music can be to help you
memorize things. I wasn't even trying to
memorize uh those Greek lyrics, but I
did because when uh it's in song form,
it's easier to remember it. When there's
some music to it, there's some rhythm,
it's easier to remember that
information. And uh I think that turning
new information into a song is a great
way to remember it, to memorize it. Uh I
can think of my son. This is another
good example. Uh he memorized his first
Bible verse by uh turning the verse into
a song. My wife and I did that. He
didn't do it, but we turned it into a
song and he was able to memorize it
after a while uh because of the song
aspect, because of the rhythm. And I've
seen other parents do that with their
children when they want them to memorize
something. They create a song for it and
then um just the fact that it's like
they're singing it makes it easier for
them to uh recall it and to recite it.
So my son memorized his first uh Bible
verse um using this technique, this
music technique. And a good example for
me um is uh in seventh grade I had this
English teacher who taught us um all of
the uh auxiliary verbs in English, the
helping verbs. And the way he taught us
these verbs was by uh turning it into
not really a song, but there was some
rhythm to it. How we would recite these
verbs. By the way, when you recite
something, it's like you're saying the
thing that you memorized. So, um he
taught us those verbs, those auxiliary
verbs. um by uh making it more rhythmic
like a song. And just to prove to you
that I can still remember these
auxiliary verbs uh even though that was
you know almost 20 years ago. Uh let me
just tell you all of the auxiliary verbs
right now. Uh the way I learned them is
amr was were be being have has had do
does shallow will should what may must
can that was basically how he taught
them to us. Yeah it's not really a song
but it kind of has like the rhythm of a
song and it's different uh from just
saying them. So the fact that it was
rhythmic like a song u made it easier to
learn and I still use that knowledge
today as an English teacher. So that's a
great example of how powerful
song and rhythm can be to help you
memorize things. And so even though I
haven't personally used music as a
language learner to learn other
languages, I think that it can be a very
helpful tool. And so if you're someone
who likes music, you like listening to
music, then this is something to
consider. um you can uh probably
incorporate
music somehow to help you learn
vocabulary and different uh things in
English, right? Um and when you do this,
you're not only learning vocabulary, you
might be learning grammatical structures
that are in that um those lyrics, right?
Uh you learn uh slang and idioms. Uh
different ways that people say things.
Um perhaps pronunciation although uh
sometimes we uh change our pronunciation
a little bit when we sing things. So I
don't really know but pronunciation as
well. And I should say that even though
I haven't intentionally
used music to learn languages, I have
learned two songs in French or not the
whole songs but most of those two songs
uh just because I like those songs and
uh the fact that I learned those songs
in French has helped me because there's
certain vocabul vabulary uh and phrases
and uh structures in those songs that uh
I use now because of those songs. Uh
I've used certain words that I learned
from those songs. Uh like I use them in
my own French conversations and I
learned them from the songs. So it
wasn't intentional, but I have actually
benefited from songs as a language
learner. So songs and music are a
powerful tool. Uh so it's something that
you can consider using uh as an English
learner. And depending on your musical
preferences, you might use a certain
type of music uh that um you can listen
to in English that can help you. Like
for example, uh I like listening to
hymns uh like spiritual songs, Christian
songs, uh the traditional Christian
music. And um I've learned some words
from Spanish hymns. Uh even though I'm
not like learning Spanish, uh when I
have been to uh Spanish church services,
uh I have learned uh like vocabulary
words from those hymns. And so, you
know, that's another example. I'm just
thinking now that I actually do have
some examples of how I've learned uh you
know, Spanish or French from music. So
again, even though I haven't done so
intentionally, uh, it's happened and
it's just because I like certain songs
or that type of music and I listen to it
and then it teaches me things. So I'm
sure you can find ways to do that with
English as well. Um, so yeah, even
though I'm not the biggest music guy, I
recognize that music is a powerful tool
that can help you learn things and
memorize things. So, you should try it
if you're interested in it. Remember
that you can get my advanced podcast
episodes by clicking on the link down
below and signing up for those. And also
check out my US Conversations podcast if
you want to practice with my
conversations that I have at normal
speed with other people. So, uh, you
should check those out. Those links are
down below. Thank you all for watching
this video and I'll talk to you in the
next